Miller, C. L. mss., 1951-1994 LMC 2397
Lilly Library
Miller, C. L. mss.
1951-1994
2004
Lilly Library
LMC 2397
10 Boxes
The Miller, C. L. mss. (1951-1994) consist primarily of correspondence, articles, drafts, and manuscripts of journalist and author Catherine Lanham Miller.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Catherine Lanham Miller (1918-2003) was born in Greensburg, Indiana and graduated from Indiana University in 1938 with a bachelor of music degree. She then went on to teach for several years until beginning a career in writing. She wrote for publications such as The American Magazine, TV Guide Magazine, Good Housekeeping, Harper's Bazaar, Ladies' Home Journal, Philadelphia Inquirer, and House Beautiful. She also wrote several books, the most notable of which being How to Say Yes to Life: A Woman's Guide to Beating the Blahs.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series: Correspondence, Writings, and Publicity.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of correspondence concerning Miller's writings, as well as proposals, drafts, and manuscripts of her writings. In addition, there are some papers concerning publicity, such as lecture notes, events, and flyers.
Related Material
See Norvelle mss. II, also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 2004
Miller, Catherine Lanham, 1918-2003
- I. CORRESPONDENCE (Box 1)
  - Mary Yost – Correspondence; notes, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Susan Potter – Correspondence; notes, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Beth Waxse - Correspondence; notes, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Book Publishers and Contract Information – Clippings (Box 1)
  - Vanity Press - Clippings (Box 1)
  - Joe and Joan Foley – Correspondence; notes, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Literary Agents, 1958-1972 (Box 1)
  - Julian Bach - Correspondence, 1972-1989 (Box 1)
  - Toni Lopopolo – Correspondence, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Besty Nolan – Correspondence; notes, clippings, 1991-1993 (Box 1)
  - Bea Moore – Correspondence; notes, clippings, 1972-1989 (Box 1)
  - Emilie Jacobson - Correspondence; notes, 1969-1985 (Box 1)
- II. WRITINGS
  - "Pretzels in the Piano" – Correspondence; chapters, notes, 1953-1969 (Box 1)
  - "Say Yes to That Dream" – Turndown Chapters, Correspondence, clippings, 1976 (Box 1)
  - "Say Yes to That Dream" – book Chapter 1, correspondence, 1972 (Box 1)
  - "Say Yes to That Dream" – book Chapter 2, writings (Box 1)
  - "Say Yes to That Dream" – book Chapter 3, writings, clippings (Box 1)
  - "Say Yes to That Dream" – book Chapter 4, clippings, writings (Box 1)
  - "Say Yes to That Dream" – book Chapter 6, Notes, writings (Box 1)
  - "Say Yes to That Dream" – book Chapter 7, Notes, clippings, writings (Box 1)
  - "Say Yes to That Dream" – book Chapter 7, Notes, clippings, writings (Box 1)
  - "Say Yes to That Dream" – book Chapter 9, notes, clippings, writings, correspondence, 1974 (Box 1)
  - "Say Yes to That Dream" – book Chapter 10, Notes, clippings (Box 1)
  - "Say Yes to That Dream" – book Chapter 11, notes, clippings, writings (Box 1)
  - "Uprooting" book- Correspondence; notes, writings and clippings, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Copy of How to Say Yes To Life: A Woman's Guide To Beating the Blahs, mimeograph copy (Box 1)
  - Old Pending – notes, clippings, correspondence, Kappa Kappa Gamma magazine, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Memos re: book – memos to friends, notes (Box 1)
  - First Publicity for Book - clippings (Box 1)
  - Releases for Use of Real Names - Correspondence, notes, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Bea Moore, 1969-1972 (Box 1)
  - First Serial Rights - correspondence, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Promotion Schedule – notes, correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Shimkin Letter and Telegram – Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Publicity Memos, Notes on Meetings - Correspondence, memos, notes, 1971 (Box 1)
  - The Mike Douglas Show – Correspondence, clippings, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Book #1 Titles and Dedications – notes (Box 1)
  - Book #1 Contract – book legalities, Release: Nancy White, Mc Call's - notes, correspondence, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Who's Who of American Women certificate, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Ploys, Segments, TV Chat - notes (Box 1)
  - Complimentary Copies Inscriptions – notes, correspondence, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Pre-book Publicity – correspondence, notes, 1968-1971 (Box 1)
  - Book Segments in Progress – writings, clippings (Box 1)
  - Book Segments in Progress cont. – writings, clippings, notes (Box 1)
  - Research on Marriage – notes, clippings (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Bill Davidson, 1973-1978 (Box 1)
  - Good Material for Writing M/W – notes, clippings (Box 1)
  - Creative Couples Book Research – notes, correspondence, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Creative Couples Book Research, Marcy and Laura – correspondence, notes, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Parenting (Melissa) – notes, clippings (Box 1)
  - "1 + 1 =3" Publisher Turndowns – writings, correspondence, 1973-1979 (Box 1)
  - Getting High On Life: A Woman's Guide To Beating the Blahs proposal, manuscript, notes (Box 2)
  - Getting High On Life: A Woman's Guide To Beating the Blahs proposal and sample chapters (Box 2)
  - Getting High On Life: A Woman's Guide To Beating the Blahs proposal and author credits (Box 2)
  - Supplemental Materials, correspondence, writings, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Soulmates: How to Find and Keep Trueblue Friends proposal (Box 2)
  - Soulmates sample chapters intro, 6, and 17 (Box 2)
  - Soulmates completed chapters 1, 2, and 9 (Box 2)
  - Too Antiquated book ideas, clippings, writings (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Avon-Merrill Lynch - correspondence, notes, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" McCall's Working Mother - correspondence, 1979 (Box 2)
  - "Indentity" proposals, writings (Box 2)
  - "Identity" National Liberty Corp. - correspondence, notes, 1978 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Universe Life Insurance - notes, correspondence, 1980 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Colonial Penn - proposal, notes, correspondence, 1979 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Nancy Farwell - correspondence, clippings, notes, 1980 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Soroptomist - correspondence, notes, 1981 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" American Management Assoc. - correspondence, 1977 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Junior League Reno - correspondence, 1981 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Denney - notes, correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Colonial Penn - correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Reiff - correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Conventions/Hotels - correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Marriott Corporation - correspondence, 1977 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" General Foods Corporation - correspondence, 1977 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Scott Paper - correspondence, 1975 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Dupont - correspondence, 1977 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Campbell Soup - correspondence, 1975 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Chilton - correspondence, notes, 1977 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Departments Stores - correspondence, 1977 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Industry Backup - correspondence, 1975 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Invitations, Big Cards, ID Logo (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Misc. Speeches Not Booked by Keedick-correspondence, notes, 1972 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Keedick Lecture Bureau, Inc. - speeches by CLM, correspondence, brochures, notes, 1973-1975 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Speeches - writings, brochures, flyers (Box 2)
  - "Identity" Spokesperson for Listerine (via Rowland) - writings, correspondence, 1973 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" articles, copies of articles (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - writings, notes, correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - legal and financial notes, finances (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Lawyer, Mason-Meeker - correspondence, notes, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Cathy Publicity, Interviews, Ploys, Dev. Adv. - correspondence, notes, 1972-1976 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Letters to Experts and Returned Copies - correspondence, 1976-1982 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Changes/Additions/Suggestions from Participants - correspondence, notes, 1976 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Carroll-Cathy-Time Management and Cathy Program Script-writing (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Time Tables, notes (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Summary of Questionnaires, evaluations, notes (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Identity Overview, writings (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Newly Edited Evaluations, comments by participants (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - "The Story of Identity," writings (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - "The 2 Day program," program schedule (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - "Identity" important papers, invitations, program schedule, information on Identity (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - coordinator materials and Cathy's Speech and intro-notes, writings, pin (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Syndication, correspondence, 1972-1981 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Nevada Appeal Readers Quotes, writings (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Flyer original, notes, flyers (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Paste-ups sets of collected columns, clippings (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Comments from professional publishers, collected-correspondence, notes, 1981 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - CC Appeal, correspondence, notes, 1980-1985 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Bonanza, correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Daily Leader, Frederick, OK-correspondence, newspaper, 1981-1985 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Greenburg Daily News, clippings, correspondence, writings, 1981-1985 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Reader mail from Appeal column, correspondence, 1981-1985 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - N.Y. Times syndicated sales, correspondence, 1983 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Sample Kit Saying Yes To Life, clippings, writings (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Dial-a-Writer/Photo Marketing Mag-brochure, correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - ASJA Book Segment, brochures, clippings, correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 2)
  - "Identity" and "Two-Three" - Philadelphia Inquirer Columns, copies of articles (Box 2)
  - Photocopy of Beating the Blahs column, 26 November 1972 (Box 3)
  - Saying YES to Life column, list of columns (Box 3)
  - Saying YES to Life column, clippings, 1980-1985; (15 folders) (Box 3)
  - Manuscript of Saying YES to Life column, 01 May 1985 (Box 3)
  - Beating the Blahs for Older Men (book) (Box 3)
  - Grandmother: A Kid's Ace in the Hole (book), manuscript and correspondence, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Fire and Ice (proposed memoir), letter publishers and related materials (Box 3)
  - Correspondence concerning Ruth and John Thomas (Box 3)
  - Untitled article concerning Lake Tahoe and the Coast Guard (Box 3)
  - Accumulated wisdom: Thoughts From an "Older Woman" (Box 3)
  - Anyone For Culture? (Box 3)
  - Are You Sure Your Child Can See? (Box 3)
  - Cordelia the Convertible (Box 3)
  - For Sale: House on a Hill (Box 3)
  - The "Honey-I've-Got-Two-on-the-Fifty-Yard-Line" Survival Plan (Box 3)
  - How to Shop With Your Teenage Daughter… and Come Out Without Hating Each Other (Box 3)
  - I Remember Ithan Valley (Box 3)
  - The Jenny-and-Ellen Survival Kit (Box 3)
  - Joyride (Box 3)
  - The Monster: A Love Story (Box 3)
  - My Husband Won't Let Me (Box 3)
  - The PTA Fashion Show (Box 3)
  - Puerto Rice??? Si, Si (Box 3)
  - Robin (Box 3)
  - Sail, Baby, Sail (Box 3)
  - Vacation Mother (Box 3)
  - What Do You Do With a Boring Husband? (Box 3)
  - What's Bothering Kids? (Box 3)
  - You and Your Realtor (Box 3)
  - Goals, or Homemaking vs. Job panel, various chapters (Box 4)
  - At My Age? (Box 4)
  - Beauty and the Beast of Video-land (Box 4)
  - Best Gift a Parent Can Give a Child (Box 4)
  - Bring the Children (Box 4)
  - The Donahues of Bayview Park (Box 4)
  - Farewell, PTA! (Box 4)
  - 500 Green Thumbs (Box 4)
  - Go Back to School…Your Child's School, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Half Past Thirteen (Box 4)
  - Hey, Fatso! (Box 4)
  - Honey, Can You Play "Down By the Old Mill Stream"? (Box 4)
  - Hospital Holiday (Box 4)
  - How To Be a Friend to Someone Who's Ill (Box 4)
  - How To Be a Guest on a Boat (And Get Invited Back) (Box 4)
  - The Man/Woman Thing in the Office (Box 4)
  - The Mouse That Turned On (Box 4)
  - Okay, Mom, Move Over (Box 4)
  - Old Piano Hits the Fast Track in Houston (Box 4)
  - The Party Jam Session (alt. title: Gut Bucket) (Box 4)
  - Purple Passion (Box 4)
  - [Realty articles] (Box 4)
  - [Retirement] (Box 4)
  - Sally Harral…Dynamic Woman!!! (Box 4)
  - The School Bus (Box 4)
  - Take a Guitar to the Airport…And See What Happens (Box 4)
  - Teamwork Provides Music For Cruise (alt.title: They Sing For Their Supper) (Box 4)
  - Telephone Tactics (Box 4)
  - That Was the Week That Wasn't (alt. title: Hooray, My Car is Sick) (Box 4)
  - Tips from an (Unpaid) Female Taxi Driver (Box 4)
  - Volunteer Jobs: Crusades or Time Fillers (Box 4)
  - We Did It (Box 4)
  - What Can I Do? (Box 4)
  - Which Way to the Nude-Colored Body Stocking With the Deliciousness of Absolutely No Control? (Box 4)
  - Working At Home (Box 4)
  - Yoga. Is That the Thing Where You Stand On Your Head? (Box 4)
  - [highway article] (Box 4)
  - Writings ideas, manuscripts, research, etc., 1951-1958 (Box 4)
  - Writings ideas, manuscripts, research, etc., 1952-1959 (Box 4)
  - Column ideas, clippings (Box 4)
  - Friendlove (proposed book), manuscripts of various chapters, research/background, etc., (31 folders) (Box 5)
  - Friendlove (proposed book) (cont'd), (9 folders) (Box 6)
  - Brainthrob (proposed book), manuscripts of various chapters, research/background, etc., (16 folders) (Box 6)
  - Cocoon, book proposal (Box 6)
  - One Plus One Equals Three: The Synergistic Power of Man/Woman Teams in the Working World, book proposal, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Getting High on Life: Beating the Blahs, book proposal, sample chapters, correspondence, misc., (5 folders) (Box 6)
  - Grandmother: A Kid's Ace in the Hole (proposed book), manuscript, partial chapters, background, research, etc., (15 folders) (Box 7)
  - How to Say YES to Life (book), manuscript, various chapters, proposal, etc., (9 folders) (Box 7)
  - Carnegie, book proposal (Box 7)
  - Woman and Identity (proposed book), proposal, background, etc., (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Love Without Lust (article), manuscript (Box 7)
  - Love Without Lust (proposed book), research, sample chapters (Box 7)
  - [Travel book], background, overview, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Book ideas (Box 7)
  - Book projects (Box 7)
  - [Building a house], correspondence about proposed article (Box 7)
  - Saying YES to Life, manuscripts of Tahiti columns, photographs, background (Box 7)
  - Poetry by Miller (Box 8)
  - Aerobics, the Coopers and You (Box 8)
  - Class reunion (Box 8)
  - Don't Mourn Lost Gardens (Box 8)
  - The Double Life of the Writing Wife (Box 8)
  - Geriatrics (Box 8)
  - I Send My Husband Packing (Box 8)
  - I'm Tired of Being the Family Gravedigger (Box 8)
  - Jack Kelly (Box 8)
  - Jet (Box 8)
  - Lea Mione Story and other ideas (Box 8)
  - Menopause: Is It Really All Down-hill From Here (Box 8)
  - Soap Opera (Box 8)
  - Telephone Tactics (Box 8)
  - The Wonderful Day That Melissa Was Four (Box 8)
  - Yes, Even Jeans (Box 8)
  - Yoga for Youngsters (Box 8)
  - Yoga articles (Box 8)
  - Article ideas, background, notes, etc., (7 folders) (Box 8)
  - Dynamic Maturity column titles (Box 8)
  - Questions for Dynamic Maturity column (Box 8)
- III. PUBLICITY
  - ASJA American Society of Journalists and Authors Lecture Bureau, miscellaneous correspondence, speech, (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Columnist speech (Box 8)
  - Travel speech (Box 8)
  - TV shows, 1973-1975 (Box 8)
  - Listerine appearances, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Printed materials about children (Box 8)
  - Writings by others, clippings (Box 8)
  - Markets for writings, (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Campbell Soup Company, correspondence (Box 8)
  - Jingles for friends (Box 8)
  - Dolan, Mary, correspondence, misc. (Box 8)
  - Norvelle, Lee, correspondence, article, misc. (Box 8)
  - Siegrist, Jack, correspondence, (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Identity, two day seminars developed by Miller for women, correspondence and other materials relating to brochure copy, experts brought in for seminars, publicity, questionnaires from participants, etc., (44 folders) (Box 9)
  - Lectures, contracts and correspondence arranged by date, (22 folders) (Box 10)
  - Lectures, publicity (Box 10)
  - Brainthrob, publicity (Box 10)
  - How to Say YES to Life, promo tour, correspondence, (16 folders) (Box 10)
  - How to Say YES to Life, publicity, (6 folders) (Box 10)
  - Philadelphia Enquirer, correspondence (Box 10)
  - Jerome Kern tribute (Box 10)
  - Promotional material for future presentation (Box 10)
  - Promotional (Box 10)
  - The Franklin Mint, (3 folders) (Box 10)
  - Gerald F. Selinger Advertising Agency (Box 10)
  - TV Guide (Box 10)
  - Young and Rubicam Advertising Agency (Box 10)
  - Advertising jobs (Box 10)
  - Biographical (Box 10)
  - Photograph, Miller and two unidentified men (Box 10)
  - Local affairs, local politics (Box 10)
  - Recreational reading (Box 10)
  - "Ross's 6th grade Halloween party" (Box 10)
  - Travel: Spring 1994, Middle East, Orient., diary, correspondence (Box 10)
  - Yoga (Box 10)